Clayton W. Seitz, PhD

cwseitz@iu.edu cwseitz.github.io

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I have a strong theoretical background in quantum computing and quantum information theory, with research experience in quantum bioimaging. Furthermore, I am a capable programmer and have experience with machine learning methods for computer vision, time series analysis, and generative modeling.

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosopy, Physics

2024

Purdue University

Master of Science, Physics

2021

University of Chicago

Bachelor of Science, Physics, Magna Cum Laude

2019

Indiana University
Minor: Mathematics

Bachelor of Science, Informatics (Math Focus), Magna Cum Laude

2019

Indiana University

EXPERIENCE

Graduate Researcher

2022-Present

Purdue University, Indianapolis, IN

- Conceptualized and implemented a novel quantum bioimaging strategy for fluorescence nanoscopy
- Developed general probabilistic models for quantum imaging experiments and associated Bayesian methods for statistical inference tasks
- Engineered novel hardware systems for widefield quantum imaging and photonics applications

Graduate Researcher

2020-2022

University of Chicago, Chicago, IL

- Investigated fundamental learning mechanisms in recurrent neural networks (RNNs) using dynamical models, mean-field theory, and time-series analysis.
- Designed and ran Monte Carlo simulations of spiking neural networks

Research Assistant

2019-2020

Purdue University, Indianapolis, IN

- Developed a scientific package in Python for high-throughput object detection and tracking
- Managed the package lifecycle and user training throughout the laboratory

AWARDS

NIH Graduate Training Fellowship University of Chicago, Chicago, IL

2020

2019

Hudson and Holland Scholarship for Diversity and Inclusion 2013-2017 Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

Founders Scholar 2013-2017 Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

Cigital Scholarship 2016-2017 Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

PUBLICATIONS Clayton Seitz and Jing Liu. Quantum enhanced localization microscopy with a single photon avalanche diode array. In Review. 2024

> Clayton Seitz[†], Donghong Fu[†], Mengyuan Liu, Hailan Ma, and Jing Liu. BRD4 phosphorylation regulates the structure of chromatin nanodomains. https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.09.03.611057. 2024

> Clayton Seitz and Jing Liu. Uncertainty-aware localization microscopy by variational diffusion. In Review. 2024

> Maelle Locatelli[†], Josh Lawrimore[†], Hua Lin[†], Sarvath Sanaullah, Clayton Seitz, Dave Segall, Paul Kefer, Salvador Moreno Naike, Benton Lietz, Rebecca Anderson, Julia Holmes, Chongli Yuan, George Holzwarth, Bloom Kerry, Jing Liu, Keith D Bonin, Pierre-Alexandre Vidi. DNA damage reduces heterogeneity and coherence of chromatin motions. PNAS 12 July 2022; 119 (29): 1-11

> Mengdi Zhang, Clayton Seitz, Garrick Chang, Fadil Iqbal, Hua Lin, and Jing Liu A guide for single-particle chromatin tracking in live cell nuclei. Cell Biology International 15 January 2022; 46 (5): 683-700

> Wenting Wu, Farooq Syed, Edward Simpson, Chih-Chun Lee, Jing Liu, Garrick Chang, Chuanpeng Dong, Clayton Seitz, Decio L. Eizirik, Raghavendra G. Mirmira, Yunlong Liu, Carmella Evans-Molina; Impact of Proinflammatory Cytokines on Alternative Splicing Patterns in Human Islets. Diabetes 25 October 2021; 71 (1): 116 - 127

> Clayton Seitz, Hailan Ma, and Jing Liu. Cytokine-induced transcriptional memory is evident in the kinetics of transcriptional bursts. Biophysical Society Annual Conference 2022

> Clayton Seitz, Hua Lin, Keith Bonin, Pierre-Alexandre Vidi, and Jing Liu. Quantifying the spatiotemporal dynamics of dUTP labeled chromatin during the DNA damage response. Biophysical Society Annual Conference 2020

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Programming Languages & Software: Linux, Bash, Python, R, PyTorch, C/C++, SQL, LaTeX, Git, Docker, SLURM, AWS, CUDA